Logan Miller

New York, NY | 203-581-1589 | logamills@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full-stack developer experienced in the MERN programming stack with a background in legal technology. Currently leading a team of engineers designing and building a POS system from the ground up. I thrive in a fast-paced environment working with like-minded people to push expectations, create, and design systems that improve user experience and present information in new and exciting ways.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, React.js, Vue, Express.js, Next.js, MongoDB, Ruby on Rails, Python, C#, ASP.NET, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, JEST, AWS, Docker, Bootstrap, Tailwind, SCSS, Git

WORK EXPERIENCE

My.Suit
Full-stack Software Engineer

New York, NY

11/2022 - Present

Key Technologies: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MsSQL, MongoDB, C#, ASP.NET

- Collaborated with business leaders to identify areas of improvement and spearheaded the development of a new POS system using the MERN stack, seamlessly integrated with the existing MsSQL database.
- Worked closely with a team of talented UI/UX designers, utilizing Figma to meticulously plan application flow and efficiently translate designs into robust code.
- Streamlined data fetching by optimizing the current MsSQL database, enabling more efficient retrieval of data.
- Contributed to the maintenance, upkeep and enhancement of the MVC ASP.NET environment in collaboration with a team of skilled engineers.
- Assumed leadership responsibilities by conducting weekly meetings to prioritize bug fixes, ensuring thorough testing
 and successful implementation prior to deployment.
- Successfully identified, resolved and validated over 50+ bug fixes, ensuring the stability and reliability of the software
- Designed and implemented over 30+ unique and mobile-responsive front-end components while simultaneously building all back-end routing and logic.

Freelance Work 04/2022 - Present

MagickCo.com

Flatiron School

- Helped build and design interactive Shopify ecommerce platform for a new energy drink company based in Utah.
- Satisfy client needs in a way that is sensitive to their timeframe and budget based on their requirements.

Software Engineer

New York, NY

04/2022 - 8/2022

Spotifinder: React.js, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, SCSS

Browse users and compare advanced Spotify analytics and top tracks/artists to see who is your closest music match

- Utilized Spotify API and OmniAuth 2.0 to authenticate users and link their Spotify account to pull advanced analytics while maintaining user privacy and security best practices.
- Designed and implemented formulas to parse data and assign numerical values to users' analytical categories in order to present data and match users based on a custom algorithm.
- Implemented conditional rendering for all mobile devices and tablets.

Kraft Kennedy

New York, NY

01/2017 - 01/2022

- Technical Writer / Sales Engineer
- Wrote technical documentation for a variety of offerings such as Azure, SQL, AWS, Microsoft 365 and more in order to streamline user experience and optimize workflow.
- Helped design systems in CRM to allow for better data analysis and organization.
- Designed a template system for all RFP responses and proposals to streamline business and increase response times.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

04/2022 - 08/2022

Cornell University

Ithaca, NY

Python Programming and Data Analytics

11/2021 - 05/2022

University of Iceland

Reykjavik, IS

Coursework completed toward Master's Degree

09/2020 - 09/2021

Pace University
Bachelor's Degree - Magna Cum Laude

New York, NY

09/2012 - 09/2016